[music]
[音乐]
Hello and welcome to section 5
您好，欢迎来到第5节
of lesson 2. Here we're going to look at the various
第2课的内容
different intermediate operations that you can use when processing a stream. As
处理流时可以使用的不同中间操作。如
you remember we talked about this
你记得我们谈论过这个
earlier in the lesson, how an intermediate operation
在本课程的前面，如何进行中间操作
takes as input a stream and generates as output a
将流作为输入并生成一个输出
sream. A stream,
re流，
as we've already found out provides a sequence of
因为我们已经发现提供了一系列
elements and we can't process that either sequentially
元素，我们既不能顺序处理
or in parallel. A lot of the
或并行。很多
operations that we will need to perform on that stream
我们将需要在该流上执行的操作
use parameters which are functional interfaces
使用函数式接口的参数
and that means that we can use Lambda expressions to define how
这意味着我们可以使用Lambda表达式来定义
we want to do the processing. The method itself tells us what we want to do in
我们要进行处理。该方法本身告诉我们我们想要做什么
the Lambda expression tells a method how to do that
Lambda表达式告诉方法
and as we'll see with examples as we go through it gives us that separation
正如我们将在示例中看到的那样，它使我们分离了
of concerns in terms of how we actually process the elements that we have
关于我们如何实际处理所拥有元素的关注
in our stream. One very important thing is that
在我们的流中。一件非常重要的事情是
the way that we handle the objects that are created in the stream
处理流中创建的对象的方式
and used in the stream is we must not modify them. So we can create new elements
并在流中使用的是我们不得修改它们。这样我们就可以创建新元素
for the output stream that's not a problem, but you mustn't modify the elements
对于输出流来说这不是问题，但您不得修改元素
of the stream otherwise we'll get a ConcurrentModificationException.
流，否则我们将获得ConcurrentModificationException。
Very often these things are typically stateless
通常，这些东西通常是无状态的
in terms of the approach to take because that is functional programming,
就采取的方法而言，因为这是函数式编程，
we don't want to introduce any state because that would then
我们不想引入任何状态，因为那样会
break the rules we have for functional programming. We can
打破函数编程的规则。我们可以
change streams from sequential to parallel and we can also go back the other way, so we
将流从顺序更改为并行，我们也可以采用其他方法，所以我们
can create parallel Stream and make it sequential or we can take sequential stream
可以创建并行流并使其按顺序进行，也可以按顺序进行
and make parallel. All processing in the pipeline
并使其平行。管道中的所有处理
is done either in sequentially or in parallel.
按顺序或并行进行。
So whichever is the last call which changes the
因此，无论哪个更改了
stream either sequentially or parallel will be the one that is used to determine
流是顺序的还是并行的将是用来确定
all the processing in the stream. Let's start with
流中的所有处理。让我们开始
filtering and mapping because we've already seen a couple of these used in some of
过滤和映射，因为我们已经看到其中一些
the examples that we've seen so far.
到目前为止我们看到的例子。
The first of those is distinct. What that will do is we'll return a stream
第一个是不同的。要做的是我们将返回流
which has no duplicate elements in it, so we will ensure that there are
其中没有重复的元素，因此我们将确保其中没有
no elements that are equal. We can use
没有相等的元素。我们可以用
filter and that will take an argument, which is a predicate;
过滤器，它将接受一个作为predicate的参数；
We've seen this used already where what we want to do
我们已经看到它已经用于我们想要做的事情
is to identify only the elements on the input stream
是仅识别输入流中的元素
that we want to pass to the output stream. The predicate
我们想要传递到输出流。predicate
will provide a method which returns a boolean
将提供一个返回布尔值的方法
and if the element that's passes to that
如果传递给那个元素
method returns true it's added to the output stream, if it
方法返回true，则将其添加到输出流
returns false it ignored. As again with the example used earlier where we had
返回false它被忽略。再次使用前面的示例
all the students who graduated in year 2011; thats a
2011年毕业的所有学生；那是一个
use of a filter  with the predicate which compares the graduation year to
使用带有predicate的过滤器，该predicate将毕业年份与
2011. Map takes
2011年。
a function and what it will do is it will take each
一个函数，它将要做的是每个函数
element on the input stream use it as
输入流上的元素将其用作
a parameter to the function and place the
函数的参数，然后将
result of that function onto the output stream.
该函数的结果到输出流上。
So it's very simple way of mapping from
因此，这是从
values on the input stream to values on the output stream.
输入流上的值到输出流上的值。
As we've already seen there is the
正如我们已经看到的那样
requirement to handle primitive types as well as object representations.
处理基本类型和对象表示的要求。
So there are three versions of that map method:
因此，该map方法有三种版本：
mapToInt, mapToDouble, mapToLong that will create streams of
mapToInt，mapToDouble，mapToLong会创建
primitive values rather than objects. Flat Maps.
原始值而不是对象。平面地图。
so I talked about map and I said that the way that
所以我谈到了地图，我说
map works is that we have a function and that function
地图的工作是我们有一个函数，那个函数
will take single value as input
将采用单个值作为输入
and generate a single value as output, so the idea is that
并生成一个值作为输出，所以这个想法是
each element on the input stream is used as a parameter to the
输入流上的每个元素都用作
function and the result is placed on the output stream. So we have a one-to-one
函数并将结果放置在输出流上。所以我们一对一
mapping. There are certain situations where
映射。在某些情况下
each elements on the input stream will create
输入流上的每个元素都会创建
its own stream of results. What we get in that case
自己的结果流。在那种情况下我们得到什么
is a stream of
是
streams, where each element creates its own stream and we end up with a stream
流，每个元素创建自己的流，最后得到一个流
of stream. That is not what we need;
流。那不是我们所需要的；
we need a single stream as the output. So in that case
我们需要一个流作为输出。所以在那种情况下
we use flapMap. What flatMap will do is take
我们使用flapMap。 flatMap将要做的是
the input stream, apply whatever one-to-many
输入流，一对多应用
mapping is required so each element in the input stream can create multiple
需要映射，以便输入流中的每个元素都可以创建多个
elements and those will then be placed on the output
元素，然后将它们放在输出上
stream and they will be concatenated together so that we have
流，它们将被连接在一起，以便我们拥有
a single output stream. But the size of the output stream
单个输出流。但是输出流的大小
could be different to the size of the input stream.
可能与输入流的大小不同。
Here we have an example how we can use flatMap.
这里有一个示例，说明如何使用flatMap。
In this case what we're trying to do is to extract words
在这种情况下，我们要尝试提取单词
from file which contains lines of text.
来自包含文本行的文件。
To do this what I've got here is
为此，我在这里得到的是
BufferedReader, which are connected to the file and then
BufferedReader，它们先连接到文件，然后
use the lines method of that, which remembers a new method now
使用该方法的lines方法，该方法现在可以记住一个新方法
which returns a stream of strings,
返回字符串流，
which are the lines of text from the BufferedReader. We pass that
这是BufferedReader中的文本行。我们通过了
into flatMap and flatMap use Lambda expression
进入flatMap和flatMap使用Lambda表达式
to determine how we're going to create this stream of streams,
确定我们将如何创建此流流，
which will be concatenated into a single stream. What we do here
它将串联成一个流。我们在这里做什么
is we pass in a single parameter, which is line; that's the line of
我们是否传递了一个参数，即line？那就是
text from file and then we create a new stream
来自文件的文本，然后我们创建一个新的流
using the of method, which is a static method on stream
使用of方法，这是流上的静态方法
and we split the line of text we have using regular expression
然后使用正则表达式拆分文本行
into the individual words. So we break it up based on spaces and tabs
变成个别单词。所以我们根据空格和制表符将其分解
and we create new stream for each line which is a stream
我们为每一行创建一个新的流
of words in that line. flatMap will then concatenate those streams
该行中的单词。然后，flatMap将连接这些流
together
一起
so the output stream from flatMap, will be
因此，flatMap的输出流将为
all the streams words from the individual
所有来自个人的信息流
lines which made up the input stream. We can possibly
组成输入流的行。我们可能
filter to eliminate zero length words and then pass it to collect to create a list.
过滤器以消除零长度的单词，然后将其传递以收集以创建列表。
we'll talk more about that when we talk about collectors in lesson 3.
在第3课中谈论收藏家时，我们将详细讨论。
Yeah we want to restrict
是的，我们要限制
the size of a stream what
流的大小是多少
we actually going to do here is use one or two methods. We can you skip,
我们实际上要做的是使用一种或两种方法。我们可以跳过吗
which will return stream, which takes the input stream but skips
这将返回流，它接受输入流但跳过
or ignores the first n
或忽略前n个
elements of the input stream. Limit
输入流的元素。限制
which also takes an argument which is a long return stream, which
这也需要一个长返回流的参数，
only contains the first n elements of the input stream.
仅包含输入流的前n个元素。
So they're kind of opposites. skip returns everything
所以它们有点相反。跳过将返回所有内容
but the first n elements at the stream, limit returns
但是流中的前n个元素，限制返回
only the first n elements of the stream. Again, if we look at an example here
流的前n个元素。再说一次，如果我们看一个例子
we've got our BufferedReader, we create a
我们有了BufferedReader，我们创建了一个
stream source from the lines from that BufferedReader
来自该BufferedReader的行的流源
and then pass it into skip with a value 2.
然后将其传递给具有值2的skip。
So that's going to do is it's going to skip the first
所以要做的是跳过第一个
two lines of the file and then pass the rest of the lines of the
文件的两行，然后传递其余的行
file to the next intermediate operation. In this case
文件到下一个中​​间操作。在这种情况下
that's limit which is only going to return the first two
那是极限，只会返回前两个
elements of that input stream. The effect of that is
该输入流的元素。的效果是
we will get lines 3 and lines 4
我们将得到第3行和第4行
passed to the terminal operation, which in this case is collect.
传递给终端操作，在这种情况下是收集操作。
Now this is a good example of
现在，这是一个很好的例子
where the way that this is processed internally
内部处理的方式
is optimised because, if
已优化，因为，如果
our file had a thousand lines in it what's not going to happen
我们的文件中有一千行不会发生
is that the lines stream source method
是线流源方法
will read all one thousand lines in the file and pass
将读取文件中的所有一千行并通过
all one thousand lines to skip. skip would then say
全部跳过一千行。跳过然后会说
skip past the first two and return 998 lines
跳过前两个并返回998行
to limit. limit within say i only need the
限制。限制内说我只需要
first two and return those first two. That will be very efficient
前两个并返回前两个。那将非常有效
so the code underneath will merge together those operations
因此下面的代码将合并这些操作
and identify that actually only the first 4 lines of the file need to be read
并确定实际上只需要读取文件的前4行
and at that point it will stop reading lines from the
然后它将停止读取
file because it will reach the limit of two after having skipped
文件，因为跳过后它将达到两个限制
the first two on the input stream. So that's
输入流中的前两个。所以那是
a good example how we can optimize. Sorting and unsorting.
一个如何优化的好例子。排序和未排序。
sorted; there is a version of this that takes a
排序有一个版本需要
Comparator and what that will do is it will take stream of
比较器及其作用是将
elements and it will then sort them based on the Comparator.
元素，然后它将根据比较器对它们进行排序。
So if we wanted to use the Comparator that we had
因此，如果我们想使用我们拥有的比较器
earlier in the Lambda section we could use the one where we
在Lambda部分的前面，我们可以使用
return difference in length and that will sort the
返回长度差，这将对
strings on the input stream by length. There's also a
输入流中按长度排列的字符串。还有一个
sorted method which takes no argument, so it doesn't
不带参数的排序方法，因此它不会
take a Comparator, in which case will sort
带一个比较器，在这种情况下会排序
based on natural order. If there's  a stream of numbers it'll
根据自然顺序。如果有数字流，它将
based on numeric order, if there's a stream of strings it'll sort it
根据数字顺序，如果有字符串流将对其进行排序
based on the order of strings. There is also an
根据字符串的顺序。还有一个
unordered method and what's this
无序方法，这是什么
might not seem particularly useful because what you're essentially saying
可能似乎并不是特别有用，因为您实际上是在说什么
is
是
get rid of any ordering that's in that stream.
摆脱该流中的任何排序。
What this is actually more useful for is
这实际上更有用的是
if you have certain operations you going to do
如果您要执行某些操作
then things like distinct and groupingBy which will deal with later on
然后诸如distinct和groupingBy之类的东西将在以后处理
in this lesson, these actually work more efficiently
在本课中，这些实际上更有效地工作
if you have an unordered stream
如果您的视频流无序
to work with. Really this is not actually changing the order,
跟...共事。真的，这实际上并没有改变顺序，
it's just changing the characteristics of
只是改变了
the stream say that it's unordered so that we don't need to
信息流说它是无序的，所以我们不需要
to do so much work internally. So that's one that
在内部做很多工作。那就是那个
you wouldn't typically use to change the functionality of your code
您通常不会使用它来更改代码的函数
you would use it to improve the efficiency. Like I say if you're using
您将使用它来提高效率。就像我说的，如果您正在使用
distinct
不同
or using groupingBy over a large set of data then
或使用分组通过对大量数据进行处理
unordered might improve the way that it works. Peek
无序可能会改善其工作方式。窥视
Observing stream elements as they go past.
观察流元素经过时的情况。
What this does is it takes the input stream
这是在做输入流
and passes it directly to the output stream. So it creates the same
并将其直接传递到输出流。所以它创建了相同的
output stream as the input stream. As it does that
输出流作为输入流。那样做
each element of the input stream is passed to the accept method
输入流的每个元素都传递给accept方法
of the consumer that's passed as a parameter to the peek method.
作为参数传递给peek方法的使用者数量。
As I've said before it's very important that the consumer does not modify
正如我之前说过的，消费者不要修改是非常重要的
the elements of the stream, so it can look at them, it can see what's going past,
流中的元素，因此它可以查看它们，可以看到发生了什么，
but it mustn't change them. This is the kind of thing that can be very useful for
但它不能改变它们。这是一种非常有用的东西
debugging
调试
which we'll talk about in lesson 3, but it's also very useful if you want to
我们将在第3课中进行讨论，但是如果您想
do more than one thing
多做一件事
with the stream, so by doing a peek if you say wanted to print out all the
与流，因此，如果您说要打印出所有
elements the stream
流元素
you could do that using a peek and still do some other processing
您可以使用窥视函数进行此操作，然后再进行其他处理
to find name values or whatever using other parts at the stream. To summarise section 5
查找名称值或使用流中其他部分的名称。总结第5节
the
的
stream interface provides you with
流接口为您提供
the aggregate operations on elements of
元素的合计运算
the stream and most to the methods that you have,
流，以及大多数您拥有的方法，
have behavior which is defined using
具有使用定义的行为
functional interface and therefore Lambda expressions. This is separating out
函数式接口，以及Lambda表达式。这是分开的
what which is the method from how,
怎样才能做到
which is the Lambda expression that is passed as a parameter to say how you want
这是作为参数传递的Lambda表达式，表示您想要的方式
filter, how you want to map and so on.
过滤器，您要如何映射等。
This a very powerful range of intermediate operations which
这是一个非常强大的中间操作范围
allows you to manipulate streams in a variety of different ways,
允许您以各种不同的方式来操纵流，
and you know everything from map, flatMap,
而且您从地图，flatMap，
sorting all those kinds of things and you can build up
整理所有这些东西，你就可以建立起来
really quite complex processing
真的很复杂的处理
from these more simple building blocks and yet still make it very readable
这些更简单的构建基块，但仍使其非常易读
very easy to understand and
非常容易理解和
that's the end of section 5.
这是第5节的结尾。